MUHAMMAD REHMAN

FRONT END DEVELOPER

EXPERIENCE

Support Worker | Creative Options Regina

DEC 2019 - DEC 2020, REGINA, SK

- Provided day to day support to clients and gave feedback about their well-being to management.
- Demonstrated organization and teamwork by defining key concerns for clients and coordinating solutions with supports and management to better support the clients.

Junior Front End Developer | Fifo App

DEC 2020 - FEB 2021, REGINA, SK

- Apart of development team to develop a dynamic and interactive website that ensure page views and good user experience.
- Designed responsive, cross-browser compatible websites using objectoriented JavaScript frameworks like React.js.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma Candidate, Web Development

SEPT 2020 - DEC 2020, TORONTO, ON

University of Regina | Bachelors in Applied Science, Major Petroleum Systems Engineering

SEPT 2014 - 2019, REGINA, SK

Centennial Merit Plus Scholarship - 2014 Fall

Saskatchewan Opportunity Undergraduate Award - 2014 Fall

Brain and Gail Saunders Entrance Award in Engineering and Applied Science - 2014 Fall

PROJECTS

GitView (https://trusting-kalam-802f3a.netlify.app/) | Lead Coder

Brief Description: A web application that takes the github username and displays the data in charts and dynamically generates a list of repos.

Tools Used: ReactJs, HTML5, SASS, JSON, JSX, Chart.js, Flip js, and github api.

Social-Network (https://social-network23.herokuapp.com/) | Lead Coder

Brief Description: A full stack MERN application that is a copy of FaceBook. It has image uploading, CRUD operations, and Auth coded into it.

Tools Used: ReactJs, GitHub, Material-UI, Node, MongoDB, Mongoose, Redux, Heroku, Express, etc.

muhammadrehman21@gmail.com 306-520-8681 linkedin.com/in/moabre github.com/moabre https://www.mo-abre.com/

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, React, Redux, Git, C++, Responsive Design, Python, Node.js, Mongo DB, MySQL

PROFILE

I am a full-stack developer, Petroleum Engineer, amateur photographer, gaming enthusiast and most succinctly: a jack of all trades.

Although I have many interests, my main passion has been web development since graduating from BrainStation's Web Development diploma program in Dec 2020.

Specifically, I love problem solving and creating impactful web services. My interests lie in both the front-end and back-end of development.